

CONTACT

- +57 314 448 7118
- ✓ sanson.saray@gmail.com
- https://maylcon.github.io/
- Maylcon's LinkedIn
- **Download Resume**

EDUCATION

2019

Universidad de los Llanos

 Specialist in Software Development

2014

Universidad de los Llanos

• Software Engineer

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages:

- Java (Spring Boot)
- Net 8
- Angular 9+

Databases:

• SQL (Oracle, SQL Server)

DevOps and Cloud:

- AWS (Lambda, DynamoDB, S3 Buckets)
- Docker

Version Control:

· Git and Git-Flow

LANGUAGES

- Spanish (Native speaker)
- English

MAYLCON RAMIREZ

SENIOR BACKEND DEVELOPER

Microservices Architecture | .NET & Java Development

ABOUT ME

A highly skilled Systems Engineer with over 9 years of experience in software development, specialising in Microservices Architecture, .NET, and Java. Proficient in leading teams and projects efficiently, continually seeking to improve and learn new cloud technologies.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Technical Leader / Software Developer

April 2021 - May 2024

Java, Angular, SQL

Colombian Institute for Educational Evaluation

(ICFES)

- Led the special projects team.
- Frontend and backend development for PLEXI and EXA projects.

Software Developer

.NET Core, Angular

January 2022 - December 2022

National Digital Agency (AND)

- Developed and maintained the citizen folder project, enhancing digital accessibility for over 100,000 citizens.
- Developed a digital signature application, reducing document processing time by 30%.

Technical Leader / Developer

Java, .NET Core, Angular, Azure

March 2020 - February 2022

ITO Software

- Research and development in SSO (WSO2, Keycloak).
- Implemented Microservices architecture (Java).
- Technical leader of the MinTic project.

Software Developer

November 2018 - March 2020

.NET Core, Angular

Everis colombia

Software Developer

May 2015 - November 2018

CODALTEC - ParqueSoft

.NET, Oracle

CERTIFICATIONS

Professional Scrum Master I | Maylcon's Scrum.org

Scrum Developer | Maylcon's Scrum Institute

Professional English | Maylcon's Bayswater